This video is for information purpose only.
Hello everyone, how are you all? I am
your own Vishal Aakash Amit Raj Sharma and
you are watching Yudh Real. In today's video,
we will understand the information about Aditya Birla's Saral Jeevan Bima. Let's
start in simple words
with the eligibility criteria. The
entry limit in the plan is from 18 years to 65
years. The premium paying
term option that you get in the plan is the first one is single par, which
means you have to pay the premium once. The second one is
regular par, which means
you have to pay the premium continuously till the policy term runs.
Then face par, which means you have to pay the premium continuously for five years.
Then there is time par, which means you have to pay the
premium continuously for 10 years. Five par and
tank par are called limited par.
Talking about the whole system in this plan, single
par, limited par, with regular par, the
maximum policy term is 40 years. The
minimum is five years. With
single par, with limited par,
you will make a flat premium in whatever your premium paying term is. With regular par
also, 5  The
minimum premium limit for you
is
Rs.5850 per year and the half yearly option means weekly cover is
Rs.70. The monthly limit you get is
Rs.500. Now when it comes to the coverage
limit here, you get a
minimum of Rs.5 lakh and the maximum
coverage option is up to Rs.2500000. You
get to see it, so it becomes clear
that this plan is not for everyone.
Normally, those who are facing problem in taking high cover and
want less coverage, then they
can look at this plan. The revival benefit is of 5
years. You get a grace period of 15 days
with the nausea mode and you get 30 days with the
if mode. Now when it comes to the
waiting period in this plan, then
you will get a waiting period of 45 days.
After 45 days of taking the policy, if there is any problem etc. then
that Aniruddha cover will
come, wait for the remaining 45 days.  They will
not only get the death benefit but you will also
not get the survival benefit. There is no provision for surrender in it
and there is never any loan. Why not
because this is a pure right plan,
meaning it is a term insurance or you can say
that term life insurance. You can add
accidental death benefit letter in it.
Then the waiting period in it will be
45 days. You will not have to wait
for the central bank and the
cover you will get here will be equivalent.
Talking about the death benefit of the best amount,
see, in the basic annualized premium,
now add 10 to it. That is, whatever
premium has been paid till the date of the policy, then
105 percent of it or the amount
which is the episode amount, understand that and
whichever is there among these will be given to the
nominee. If you have the option on limited or
regular, you would have taken the option of premium
paying term, if you have taken the option on single, then
125 percent of your single premium, that is, 125 percent will be taken out
or the add amount which is your understanding,
whatever it is.  Normally, you will get to
see it like this, you will get its complete PDF
on the Telegram channel or the link
is given in the description,
you can also read it by downloading, so always remember one thing,
others have also not explained that
insurance is a protection and production is
never incomplete,
thank you very much, many thanks, rest maybe
I have already talked about it
in some previous video.